So let's recap. We have the following problem: we are watching a TV show and we have
我们来重温一下 现在有以下问题 我们在看一个电视节目
a long term memory which is that the show is about nature
我们有一个长期记忆 即记得这个节目是关于自然
and science and lots of forest animal have appeared.
和科学的 而且里面出现了很多动物
We also have a short term memory which is what we have
我们还有一个短期记忆
recently seen which is squirrels and trees.
也就是我们记得最近看到的东西 也即松鼠和树
And we have a current event which is what we just saw,
还有一个当前事件 即刚看到的东西
the image of a dog which could also be a wolf.
也就是一条狗的图像 但那也有可能是一头狼
And we want these three things to combine to form a prediction of what our image is.
我们想将这三者合并起来 从而预测图像是什么
In this case, the long term memory which says that the show is about
在这个案例中 长期记忆 即说明这个节目是关于森林动物的记忆
forest animals will give us a hint that the picture is of a wolf and not a dog.
暗示我们图像是一头狼 而不是一条狗
We also want the three pieces of information, long term memory,
我们还想用这三个信息 长期记忆、
short term memory, and the event,
短期记忆和事件
to help us update the long term memory.
来帮我们更新长期记忆
So let's say we keep the fact that the show is about
假设我们只记得节目是关于自然的
nature and we forget that it's about science.
但忘了它是关于科学的
And we also remember that the show is about
我们还记得这个节目是关于森林动物和树木的
forest animals and trees since we recently saw a tree.
因为我们最近看到了一棵树
So we add a bit and remove a bit to the long term memory.
所以我们给长期记忆加了点东西 也减了点东西
And finally we also want to use
最后我们还想用
these three pieces of information to help us update the short term memory.
这三种信息来帮自己更新短期记忆
So let's say in our short term memory you want to
假设对于短期记忆 你想
forget that the show has trees and remember
忘记节目里有树 记住
that it has wolves since the trees happened a few images ago and we just saw a wolf.
里面有狼 因为树是几张图像前出现的 而我们刚看到一头狼
So basically we have an architecture like this and we
基本上我们就得到了一个像这样的结构
use even more animals to represent our stages of memory.
我们来用更多动物代表不同的记忆阶段
The long term memory is represented by an elephant since elephants have long term memory.
长期记忆用一头大象表示 因为大象有长期记忆
The short term memory will be represented by
短期记忆用
a forgetful fish and the event will still be represented by the Wolf we just saw.
善忘的鱼儿表示 事件则仍用我们刚看到的狼来表示
So LSTM works as follows: the three pieces of information go inside
所以 LSTM 的工作原理是 这三种信息进入到节点里
the node and then some math happens and
进行了些数学运算
then the new pieces of information get updated and come out.
之后信息得到更新并输出出来
There is a long term memory,
这是长期记忆、
a short term memory and the prediction of the event.
短期记忆和事件预测
More specifically the architecture of the LSTM contains a few gates.
更具体地说 LSTM 结构包括几个门
It contains a forget gate,
一个遗忘门、
a learn gate, a remember gate, and a use gate.
一个学习门、一个记忆门和一个使用门
And here's basically how they work.
这些门的基本工作原理如下
So the long term memory goes to
长期记忆进入遗忘门
the forget gate where it forgets everything that it doesn't consider useful.
忘记它认为没有用处的一切
The short term memory and the event are joined together in the learn gate,
短期记忆和事件在学习门里合并到一起
containing the information that we've recently
囊括了我们刚学到的东西
learned and it removes any unnecessary information.
并移除掉一切不必要的信息
Now the long term memory that we haven't forgotten yet plus the new
然后 我们还没遗忘的长期记忆和
information that we've learned get joined together in the remember gate.
刚学到的新信息会在记忆门里合并到一起
This gate puts these two together and since it's called remember gate,
这个门把这两者放到一起 由于它叫记忆门
what it does is it outputs an updated long term memory.
所以它会输出更新后的长期记忆
So this is what we'll remember for the future.
这就是我们未来会记住的事情
And finally, the use gate is the one that decides
最后 使用门会决定
what information we use from what we previously
要从之前知道的信息
know plus what we just learned to make
以及刚学到的信息中挑出什么来使用
a prediction so it also takes those inputs the long term memory,
从而作出预测 所以它也接受长期记忆
and the new information joins them and decides what to output.
和新信息的输入 把它们合并到一起并决定要输出什么
The output becomes both the prediction and the new short term memory.
所以输出就包括了预测和新的短期记忆
And so the big unfolded picture that we have is as
我们来站在更高的角度观察这个具体过程
follows: we have the long term memory and
我们有长期记忆和
the short term memory coming in which we call LTM and STM.
短期记忆输入进来 我们把它们分别叫做 LTM 和 STM
And then an event and an output are coming in and out of the LSTM.
然后一个事件和一个输出会在 LSTM 里进出
And then this passes to the next node,
然后这些会进入下一个节点
and so on and so forth.
循环往复
So in general at time t we label everything with
总地来说 到了 t 时 我们会把所有东西
an underscore t as we can see information passes from time t -1 to time t.
都下标 t 如图 信息会从 t - 1 时传递到 t 时